{
  "lessons": {
    "Test 1: Identification": [
      {"type":"id","question":"The person called the 'Father of Data Warehouse'.","answer":"Bill Inmon"},
      {"type":"id","question":"A data warehouse feature where data is only addeed but not change or deleted.","answer":"Source Layer"},
      {"type":"id","question":"A smaller part of a data warehouse for one department (e.g., sales).","answer":"Data Mart"},
      {"type":"id","question":"The central storage of clean and integrated data.","answer":"Data Warehouse"},
      {"type":"id","question":"A schema with simple, denomarlized tables that is easy to query.","answer":["Star Schema", "Star"]},
      {"type":"id","question":"The approach that starts with an enterprise-wide data model.","answer":["Inmon's Top-Down", "Inmon", "Top-Down"]},
      {"type":"id","question":"The table that stores numbers like sales amount or quantity.","answer":["Fact-Table", "Fact Table", "Fact"]},
      {"type":"id","question":"The ETL step where data is cleaned and changed into the right format.","answer":["Transform"]},
      {"type":"id","question":"A schema where dimension tables are broken down into smaller tables.","answer":["Snowflakes Schema", "Snowflakes"]},
      {"type":"id","question":"A method that combines cloud and local storage for data warehousing.", "answer":["Hybrid"]}
    ],
    "Test 2: Multiple Choice": [
      {"type":"mcq","question":"Which is NOT a feature of a data warehouse?","choices":["Subject-Oriented","Volatile","Integrated","Time-Variant"],"answer":1},
      {"type":"mcq","question":"In the top-down approach, data marts are:","choices":["Independent from the warhouse","Built after the warehouse","Built first, then combined later","Not needed"],"answer":1},
      {"type":"mcq","question":"Main advantage of the Kimball approach:","choices":["Single source of truth","Quick to build and easy to use","Needs very skilled staff","Low redundancy"],"answer":1},
      {"type":"mcq","question":"Which schema is denomarlized and good for fast query?","choices":["Star Schema","Snowflakes Schema","Hybrid Schema","Normalized OLTP Schema"],"answer":0},
      {"type":"mcq","question":"ETL staging area is mainly for:","choices":["Long-term storage","Cleaning and transforming data","Direct reporting","Storing live transaction"],"answer":1},
      {"type":"mcq","question":"A fact table contains:","choices":["Business processes","Historical attributes","Numbers (measures) and foreign keys","Only metadata"],"answer":2},
      {"type":"mcq","question":"Example of a dimension table:","choices":["Sales Fact","Product Dimension","ETL log","Staging record"],"answer":1},
      {"type":"mcq","question":"Benefit of a hybrid data warehouse.","choices":["Higher redundancy","Flexible and parallel development","Limited scalability","Only on-premises use"],"answer":1},
      {"type":"mcq","question":"SCD Type 2 means:","choices":["Old data is replaced","Old data is kept with history","Duplicates are deleted","Data is never updated"],"answer":1},
      {"type":"mcq","question":"The bottomm-Up approach:","choices":["Starts with enterprise model","Builds small marts first","Needs more ETL","Rarely used today"],"answer":1},
      {"type":"mcq","question":"Star Schema is best for:","choices":["Handling large hierarchies","Fast and simple queries","Zero redundancy","Transaction system"],"answer":1},
      {"type":"mcq","question":"Inmon's Top-Down is often used in:","choices":["Banking(Customer data unification)","Retail(departments sales marts","Healthcare (hybrid sstyle)","Logistics (supply chain marts)"],"answer":0},
      {"type":"mcq","question":"ETL Transform step includes:","choices":["Extract","Transform","Load","Clean"],"answer":1},
      {"type":"mcq","question":"Schema most storage-efficient (normalized)","choices":["Star","Snowflake","Hybrid","Flat"],"answer":1},
      {"type":"mcq","question":"Which is NOT an advantage of Top-Down?","choices":["Single source of truth","Low redundancy","Quick to implement","Enterprise-wide reporting"],"answer":2},
      {"type":"mcq","question":"Conformed dimensions are:","choices":["Unique per department","Shared across marts","Temporary straging tables","Used only in snowflake schema"],"answer":1},
      {"type":"mcq","question":"Kimball approach is often used in:","choices":["Healthcare","Retail sales and inventory","Banking integration","Government census"],"answer":1},
      {"type":"mcq","question":"In hybrid approach, sensitive data is stored","choices":["Cloud only","On-premises (local systems)","In marts only","ETL logs"],"answer":1},
      {"type":"mcq","question":"The grain of a fact table means","choices":["Storage size","Level of detail per record","Metadata","Rule for transformation"],"answer":1},
      {"type":"mcq","question":"Which is not a business use of data warehousing?","choices":["Financial forecasting","Social media posting","Supply chain monitoring","Customer segmentation"],"answer":1}
    ],
    "Test 3: Enumeration":[
        {"type":"enum","question":"Four characteristics of a data warehouse.","answer":["Subject-Oriented","Non-Volatile","Integrated","Time-Variant"],"answerCount":4,"requiredCount":4},
        {"type":"enum","question":"Three steps of ETL.","answer":["Extract","Transform","Load"],"answerCount":3,"requiredCount":3},
        {"type":"enum","question":"Two common types of schemas used in data warehouse design","answer":["Star Schema","Star","Snowflakes Schema","Snowflakes", "Snowflake"],"answerCount":2,"requiredCount":2},
        {"type":"enum","question":"What are the two basic type of tables in dimensional modeling?","answer":["Fact Table","Fact","Dimension Table","Dimension"],"answerCount":2,"requiredCount":2},
        {"type":"enum","question":"Enumerate the three main data warehouse design methodology","answer":["Inmon's Top Down","Inmon's Top-Down","Inmon","Top-Down","Top Down","Kimball's Bottom Up","Kimball's Bottom-Up", "Kimball", "Hybrid"],"answerCount":3,"requiredCount":3},
        {"type":"enum","question":"What are the four basic components of a data warehouse system?","answer":["Data Source","Staging Area","Data Warehouse","DataWarehouse", "Datamart", "Data Mart"],"answerCount":4,"requiredCount":4},
        {"type":"enum","question":"What are the types of data marts based on their sources of data?","answer":["Dependent","Independent","Hybrid"],"answerCount":3,"requiredCount":3}
    ],
    "All Items":[
        {"type":"id","question":"The person called the 'Father of Data Warehouse'.","answer":"Bill Inmon"},
        {"type":"id","question":"A data warehouse feature where data is only addeed but not change or deleted.","answer":"Source Layer"},
        {"type":"id","question":"A smaller part of a data warehouse for one department (e.g., sales).","answer":"Data Mart"},
        {"type":"id","question":"The central storage of clean and integrated data.","answer":"Data Warehouse"},
        {"type":"id","question":"A schema with simple, denomarlized tables that is easy to query.","answer":["Star Schema", "Star"]},
        {"type":"id","question":"The approach that starts with an enterprise-wide data model.","answer":["Inmon's Top-Down", "Inmon", "Top-Down"]},
        {"type":"id","question":"The table that stores numbers like sales amount or quantity.","answer":["Fact-Table", "Fact Table", "Fact"]},
        {"type":"id","question":"The ETL step where data is cleaned and changed into the right format.","answer":["Transform"]},
        {"type":"id","question":"A schema where dimension tables are broken down into smaller tables.","answer":["Snowflakes Schema", "Snowflakes"]},
        {"type":"id","question":"A method that combines cloud and local storage for data warehousing.", "answer":["Hybrid"]},
        {"type":"mcq","question":"Which is NOT a feature of a data warehouse?","choices":["Subject-Oriented","Volatile","Integrated","Time-Variant"],"answer":1},
        {"type":"mcq","question":"In the top-down approach, data marts are:","choices":["Independent from the warhouse","Built after the warehouse","Built first, then combined later","Not needed"],"answer":1},
        {"type":"mcq","question":"Main advantage of the Kimball approach:","choices":["Single source of truth","Quick to build and easy to use","Needs very skilled staff","Low redundancy"],"answer":1},
        {"type":"mcq","question":"Which schema is denomarlized and good for fast query?","choices":["Star Schema","Snowflakes Schema","Hybrid Schema","Normalized OLTP Schema"],"answer":0},
        {"type":"mcq","question":"ETL staging area is mainly for:","choices":["Long-term storage","Cleaning and transforming data","Direct reporting","Storing live transaction"],"answer":1},
        {"type":"mcq","question":"A fact table contains:","choices":["Business processes","Historical attributes","Numbers (measures) and foreign keys","Only metadata"],"answer":2},
        {"type":"mcq","question":"Example of a dimension table:","choices":["Sales Fact","Product Dimension","ETL log","Staging record"],"answer":1},
        {"type":"mcq","question":"Benefit of a hybrid data warehouse.","choices":["Higher redundancy","Flexible and parallel development","Limited scalability","Only on-premises use"],"answer":1},
        {"type":"mcq","question":"SCD Type 2 means:","choices":["Old data is replaced","Old data is kept with history","Duplicates are deleted","Data is never updated"],"answer":1},
        {"type":"mcq","question":"The bottomm-Up approach:","choices":["Starts with enterprise model","Builds small marts first","Needs more ETL","Rarely used today"],"answer":1},
        {"type":"mcq","question":"Star Schema is best for:","choices":["Handling large hierarchies","Fast and simple queries","Zero redundancy","Transaction system"],"answer":1},
        {"type":"mcq","question":"Inmon's Top-Down is often used in:","choices":["Banking(Customer data unification)","Retail(departments sales marts","Healthcare (hybrid sstyle)","Logistics (supply chain marts)"],"answer":0},
        {"type":"mcq","question":"ETL Transform step includes:","choices":["Extract","Transform","Load","Clean"],"answer":1},
        {"type":"mcq","question":"Schema most storage-efficient (normalized)","choices":["Star","Snowflake","Hybrid","Flat"],"answer":1},
        {"type":"mcq","question":"Which is NOT an advantage of Top-Down?","choices":["Single source of truth","Low redundancy","Quick to implement","Enterprise-wide reporting"],"answer":2},
        {"type":"mcq","question":"Conformed dimensions are:","choices":["Unique per department","Shared across marts","Temporary straging tables","Used only in snowflake schema"],"answer":1},
        {"type":"mcq","question":"Kimball approach is often used in:","choices":["Healthcare","Retail sales and inventory","Banking integration","Government census"],"answer":1},
        {"type":"mcq","question":"In hybrid approach, sensitive data is stored","choices":["Cloud only","On-premises (local systems)","In marts only","ETL logs"],"answer":1},
        {"type":"mcq","question":"The grain of a fact table means","choices":["Storage size","Level of detail per record","Metadata","Rule for transformation"],"answer":1},
        {"type":"mcq","question":"Which is not a business use of data warehousing?","choices":["Financial forecasting","Social media posting","Supply chain monitoring","Customer segmentation"],"answer":1},
        {"type":"enum","question":"Four characteristics of a data warehouse.","answer":["Subject-Oriented","Non-Volatile","Integrated","Time-Variant"],"answerCount":4,"requiredCount":4},
        {"type":"enum","question":"Three steps of ETL.","answer":["Extract","Transform","Load"],"answerCount":3,"requiredCount":3},
        {"type":"enum","question":"Two common types of schemas used in data warehouse design","answer":["Star Schema","Star","Snowflakes Schema","Snowflakes", "Snowflake"],"answerCount":2,"requiredCount":2},
        {"type":"enum","question":"What are the two basic type of tables in dimensional modeling?","answer":["Fact Table","Fact","Dimension Table","Dimension"],"answerCount":2,"requiredCount":2},
        {"type":"enum","question":"Enumerate the three main data warehouse design methodology","answer":["Inmon's Top Down","Inmon's Top-Down","Inmon","Top-Down","Top Down","Kimball's Bottom Up","Kimball's Bottom-Up", "Kimball", "Hybrid"],"answerCount":3,"requiredCount":3},
        {"type":"enum","question":"What are the four basic components of a data warehouse system?","answer":["Data Source","Staging Area","Data Warehouse","DataWarehouse", "Datamart", "Data Mart"],"answerCount":4,"requiredCount":4},
        {"type":"enum","question":"What are the types of data marts based on their sources of data?","answer":["Dependent","Independent","Hybrid"],"answerCount":3,"requiredCount":3}
    ]
  }
}